Don Alonzo Sanford Papers 1812-1983 1870-1915
University of Arizona Library Special Collections
- Series VII: Financial Records, 1879-1955 (bulk 1880-1915)
  - Bank deposit slips (Nogales), 1911-1914 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Bonds, 1885, 1923 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Charitable donations, 1915 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Checks (Los Angeles), 1883-1887 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Checks (Nogales), 1894 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Checks (Nogales), 1895 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Checks (Nogales), 1896 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Checks (Nogales), 1897 (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Checks (Tucson), 1879 (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Checks (Tucson), 1880 (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Checks (Tucson), 1881 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Checks (Tucson), 1882 (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - Checks (Tucson), 1883 (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - Checks (Tucson), 1884 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Checks (Tucson), 1885-1886 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Checks (Tucson), 1885-1888 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Checks (Tucson), 1888-1889 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Checks (Tucson), 1890 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Checks (Tucson), 1891 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Checks (Tucson), 1892 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Checks (Tucson), 1893-1894 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Checks (Tucson), 1895 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Checks (Tucson), 1896-1897 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Checks (Washington, D.C.), 1872-1896 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Checks (Washington, D.C.), 1900 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Checks (Washington, D.C.), 1901 (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Checks (Washington, D.C), 1902 (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - Checks (Washington, D.C.), 1903 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Checks (Washington, D.C.), 1904 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Checks (Washington, D.C.), 1905, 1909 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Checks (Washington, D.C., New York and Virginia), 1903 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Checks (Washington, D.C. and Virginia), January-July 1904 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Checks (Washington, D.C. and Virginia), August-December 1904 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Checks (Wichita), 1891-1892 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Check registers and checkbooks, 1883-1907 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Check registers and checkbooks, 1907-1914 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Check stubs, 1883-1907 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Deposit slips (Tucson), 1914-1919 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Deposit slips (Washington, D.C.), 1895-1910, 1914 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Estate of Don A. Sanford income statements, 1923-1934 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Estate of Don A. Sanford income statements, 1940-1947 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Estate of Don A. Sanford income statements, 1948-1951 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Estate of Don A. Sanford income statements, 1954-1955 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Hudson and Company bank—“lockbox 54", 1884-1889 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Inventories of assets, 1915-1921 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Lists, 1883-1898 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Loans, 1904-1907 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Monte Pio (pawn shop) tickets (Tucson), 1879 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Promissory notes, 1866-1893 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Receipts—Acme/Arcade Laundry (Washington, D.C.), 1916 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Receipts—Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Co. (Washington, D.C.), 1909-1917 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Receipts—post office (Tucson), 1877, 1884-1889 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Receipts—Potomac Electric Power Company (Washington, D.C.), 1916-1922 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Receipts—Sanford, Louisa Bloxton, 1901-1917 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Receipts—Washington Gas Light Company, 1902-1909 (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Receipts—Washington Gas Light Company, 1914-1922 (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Record of purchases (Arizona), 1919 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Rental income statements (Tucson), 1905-1907 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Rental income statements (Tucson), 1908-1909 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Securities, stocks and notes ledger, 1882-1885 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Statement of financial condition, 1891 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Stock certificate, 1882-1910 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Taxes—assessment list, Pima County, 1889 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Taxes—assessments and tax returns (Washington, D.C.), 1902-1915 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Taxes—certificates of sale (Washington, D.C.), 1904-1910 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Taxes—Louisa Bloxton Sanford tax assessments, 1899-1916 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Taxes—notes and lists, 1882-1920 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Taxes—property tax correspondence (Tucson), 1889, 1891 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Taxes—receipts, Santa Cruz and Pima counties, Arizona, 1895-1913 (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Taxes—schedules of personal property (Washington, D.C), 1908-1914 (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Taxes—tax appraisal appeals (Washington, D.C.), 1892-1905 (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - Taxes—tax assessments and receipts (Arizona), 1881-1912 (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - Taxes—tax assessment lists, 1895-1912 (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - Taxes—tax certificates and tax deeds, 1906-1920 (Box 61, Folder 18)
  - Taxes—tax payment receipts (Honeoye Falls, New York), 1867, 1870 (Box 61, Folder 19)
  - Taxes—tax payment receipts (Washington, D.C.), 1899, 1907 (Box 61, Folder 20)
  - Tombstone city bonds, 1883-1891 (Box 61, Folder 21)
  - Tucson Opera House mortgage bonds, 1882-1892 (Box 61, Folder 22)
- Series VIII: Family Records, 1812-1977 (bulk 1865-1915)
  This series contains material of various Sanford family members, including Don and Louisa Sanford’s children (Ada, Etta, Amo, Mabel, Bertha and Don, Jr.) Materials from extended family, including Sanford’s children, grandchildren and extended family, include various writings, promissory notes, genealogical research and miscellaneous family materials. Louise McKee Summers’ (granddaughter of Don Alonzo Sanford) assorted notes about her husband Richard Summers writings are also included. This series is organized alphabetically by subject. Items within each folder are arranged chronologically.
  - Bloxton, Robert V.—military exemption card, 1864 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Death of Don and Louisa Sanford’s infant daughter Ada, 1880 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Latimer, Guy—clipping, undated (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - McKee, Amita—writings, 1923 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Miller, Leroy—clippings and notes, 1925-1945 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1877-1918 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous business and calling cards, 1879-1900 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Packard, Arba—Glenmore Farm, Virginia, 1887-1915 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Sanford, Amo, Bertha, Etta and Mabel—receipts, 1895-1907 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Sanford, Denton G.—funeral notice, 1885 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Sanford, Don A.—appointment as Deputy Sheriff, Monroe County, New York, 1868 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Sanford, Don A.—biographical information and obituary (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - Sanford, Don A.—calling cards, circa 1865-1890 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - Sanford, Don A., 1915 (Box 62, Folder 14)
  - Sanford, Don A.—drawings and writings, undated (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - Sanford, Don A., Jr.—calling cards and business cards, circa 1900-1915 (Box 62, Folder 16)
  - Sanford, Don A., Jr.—miscellaneous materials, 1897-1915 (Box 62, Folder 17)
  - Sanford family genealogical information, undated (Box 62, Folder 18)
  - Sanford family—promissory notes, 1812-1866 (Box 62, Folder 19)
  - Sanford family—research materials (Box 62, Folder 20)
  - Sanford, Greta—account ledger, 1920, 1949-1952 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Sanford, Greta—notes, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Sanford, Louisa Jane Bloxton—calling cards, circa 1865-1880 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Sanford, Louisa Jane Bloxton—proverb book, 1874 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Sanford Latimer, Mabel—funeral flower, 1918 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Sanford Latimer, Mabel—palm reading diagram, undated (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Sanford McKee, Amo—drawings and writings, obituary clipping, undated (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Sanford Miller, Bertha—bank statements and checks, 1941-1947 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Sanford Miller, Bertha—receipts, , 1917-1958 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Sanford Miller, Bertha—receipts—The Jackson Health Resort, 1910 (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Sanford Miller, Bertha—sandwich business, 1904 (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Sanford Miller, Bertha—scrapbook (photocopy), circa 1920 (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - Summers, Louise McKee—diaries, 1931-1933 (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - Summers, Louise McKee—miscellaneous, 1959-1977, undated (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - Summers, Louise McKee—notes on Richard Summers’ writings, undated (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - “The Sanford Association of America” reunion, 1909 (Box 63, Folder 16)
- Series IX: Photographs and negatives, 1874-1983 (bulk 1890-1915)
  This series contains photographs of various members of the Sanford family as well as photographs of Sanford’s ranch land, including the Stock Valley Ranch and the 97 Ranch in Patagonia, Arizona. Also included are photographs of Tucson, San Xavier del Bac and Altar, Mexico in the early 20th century. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject. Photographs within each folder are arranged chronologically.
  - 97 Ranch, Patagonia, Arizona, 1917 (Box 63, Folder 17)
  - 97 Ranch, Patagonia, Arizona, 1972 (Box 63, Folder 18)
  - Bloxton, Emmit, 1875 (Box 63, Folder 19)
  - Lulley Springs, Tyndall Mining, Santa Rita Mountains, Arizona, undated (Box 63, Folder 20)
  - Miller, Leroy, 1914-1928 (Box 63, Folder 21)
  - Monthan’s Ranch and Cuprite Mine, Santa Rita Mountains, Arizona, undated (Box 63, Folder 22)
  - Patagonia, Arizona, 1917, 1923 (Box 63, Folder 23)
  - Ranch—Patagonia, circa 1900, 1925, undated (Box 63, Folder 24)
  - Sanford, Don Alonzo, circa 1870-1894 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Sanford, Don Alonzo and Louisa Bloxton Sanford with daughters, circa 1900 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Sanford, Don, Jr.—97 Ranch, Patagonia, Arizona, 1911-1912 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Sanford, Don, Jr.—97 Ranch, Patagonia, Arizona, 1912 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Sanford Miller, Bertha—ranch in Patagonia/ trip to Altar, Mexico, 1925 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Sanford, Louisa Jane Bloxton, 1874, circa 1910 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Sanford Garber, Etta and family, 1907, 1910, 1931, undated (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Sanford Latimer, Mabel, 1901-1906 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Sanford Latimer, Mabel—album, 1899-1903, 1910-1922, undated (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Sanford McKee, Amo and family, circa 1880, 1924, undated (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Sanford Miller, Bertha, 1901-1964, undated (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Sanford Miller, Bertha—Ashburn Ranch, Patagonia, 1922, 1928, undated (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Sanford Miller, Bertha—miscellaneous negatives, circa 1910-1928 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Sanford Miller, Bertha—San Xavier del Bac, Tumacácori, Patagonia ranch, Phoenix, 1923 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Sanford Miller, Bertha—trip to Los Angeles, California, 1912 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Sanford Miller, Bertha—trip to Los Angeles, California, 1912 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Sanford Miller, Bertha—trip to Spokane, Washington, 1912 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Sanford Miller, Bertha—trip to Tennessee, 1918 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Stock Valley Ranch, 1895 (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Stock Valley Ranch, 1983 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Tucson, Arizona, 1903-1921, undated (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Tucson High School, circa 1950’s (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified people, circa 1870-1912 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified people, circa 1912-1964 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Unidentified people, circa 1940-1954 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Various Sanford family members, circa 1878-1909 (Box 66, Folder 5)
- Series X: Oversize materials, 1870-1907, (bulk 1895-1905)
  This series contains large maps, blueprints, drawings and a printed broadside. The auction broadside details Don A. Sanford’s selling of his household goods in order to leave New York State to run cattle in Texas and settle in Arizona. Maps in this series detail ranch lands around Sonoita and Patagonia, including plat maps from the San Jose de Sonoita land grant and Baca Float. In addition, some maps and drawings from circa 1900 Tucson are present. Blueprints and architectural drawings of two of Sanford’s buildings in Washington, D.C. (The Arizona and Hotel Patience/The Rochester) are also included. In addition, an autographed copy of Temperance activist Carry A. Nation’s book “The Use and Need of the Life of Carry A. Nation” given to Louisa Sanford in 1907 is present. Included here are leather gloves worn by Don A. Sanford on October 5, 1875 when he wed Louisa Jane Bloxton in Tucson. This series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Auction broadside, Honeoye Falls, New York, circa 1870 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Maps—ranch—Patagonia and Sonoita, Arizona, circa 1895 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Maps—Tucson, Arizona, circa 1900 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Sanford, Don Alonzo— leather wedding gloves, 1875 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - “The Use and Need of the Life of Carry A. Nation” by Carry A. Nation, 1905, inscribed to Mrs. Sanford, May 19, 1907 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Arizona Hotel (Washington, D.C.)— blueprints and drawings, circa 1895-1905 (Drawer 6, Folder 1)
  - Hotel Patience/The Rochester Hotel (Washington, D.C.)—blueprints and drawings, circa 1900- 1905 (Drawer 6, Folder 2)
  - ranch in Patagonia/San Jose de Sonoita land grant/Baca Float/Sonoita Valley—plat maps and Drawings, circa 1890, 1906 (Box 6, Folder 3)